It's important to have a comprehensive approach to maintaining the CIA Triad
confidentiality, integrity and availability.
These are the foundations of the cybersecurity domain
Confidentiality means that no private information
has been disclosed to unauthorized individuals.
We need to ensure that personally identifiable
information also known as PI I is protected
if you are part of a security team,
your goal is to protect the assets or
the information of large corporations or multiple individuals.
For example, if you work in banking health care or insurance companies,
you have multiple personal identifiers to protect
Integrity,
ensures that this information is not being corrupted
or changed without the information owner's permission.
It confirms that the information being maintained is complete and
accurate and consistent with the legitimate use of that information.
Interfering with the integrity of information can have serious ramifications.
For example, someone without authority changes someone's medical information
and now a patient may be in
jeopardy because someone changed that vital information.
Our job is to maintain the security of that
information so that no one unless authorized to do so
changes any part of the information we are protecting
availability is critical because it is essential that authorized users
have access to important information in a timely manner.
Cyber attacks that disrupt services often target the availability of data.
A
business cannot function if its employees and customers
cannot access their information in a timely manner.
A ransomware attack, for example,
may lock up a system and block access to vital information and services
that access will not be restored until a payment is made.